Guide to the William E. Irwin Photograph Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; Series VI; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - City of Rocks
    - View of a rock formations with mountains in the background, probably at the City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Exterior portrait of three women posed standing and standing among rock formations, probably at the City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - Exterior portrait of a woman posed sitting on a rock, probably at the City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 318)
  - Fort Bayard
    - View of Fort Bayard, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 319)
      Inscription in negative: "Ft. Bayard, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
  - Gila River
    - View of the Gila River between on a highway between Silver City and Springerville, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 320)
      Inscription in negative: "Along the Gila River, on the Silver City Springerville Highway, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of the Gila River between on a highway between Silver City and Clifton, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 321)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "The Gila Riv. Bridge along the Silver City Clifton Highway, Irwin"
  - Grant County
    - View of a man and dog driving a donkey train on a trail loaded with ore from the Apache Box Mine, Grant County, New Mexico, circa 1912-1915; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 322)
  - Kneeling Nun
    - View of the Kneeling Nun, a rock formation near Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 323)
      Inscription in negative: "The Kneeling Nun, near Santa Rita, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of the Kneeling Nun, a rock formation near Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 324)
    - View of the Kneeling Nun, a rock formation near Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 325)
  - Mescalero
    - View of American Indian police cabins at Mescalero, New Mexico, 1902; 1 unmounted photographic print and 1 hand colored unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 326)
  - Mimbres River
    - View of the Mimbres River in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 327)
      Inscription in negative: "Along the Mimbers Riv., N. M., Photo by Ed Irwin"
  - Needle's Eye
    - View of the Needle's Eye, an arch carved through a rock formation on the highway between Silver City and Clifton, New Mexico, with an automobile, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 328)
      Inscriptions on verso of a print: "By Ed Irwin, 1702 E. 1st St., Tucson, Ariz., Picture #5"
    - View of the Needle's Eye, an arch carved through a rock formation on the highway between Silver City and Clifton, New Mexico, with an automobile, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 329)
    - View of the Needle's Eye, an arch carved through a rock formation on the highway between Silver City and Clifton, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 330)
  - Pinos Altos
    - View of Pinos Altos, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 331)
      Inscription in negative: "Pino Altos, N.M., looking north, Irwin"
    - View of Cherry Creek near Pinos Altos, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 332)
    - View of Cherry Creek, near Pinos Altos, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 333)
      Inscription in negative: "Cherry Creek, near Pinos Altos, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
  - Sacramento Mountains
    - Exterior portrait of two men, man on the right identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, posed standing and holding rifles next to a hanging deer carcass and five wild turkey carcasses - two men standing, holding rifles, one buck and a number of turkeys strung on a tree, circa 1904-1910; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 334)
      Inscription in negative: "Deer and turkey hunting in the Sacramento Mts., N. M., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of a train of the Alamogordo and Sacramento Mountain Railway on a wood trestle in the Sacramento Mountains Climbing the Sacramento Mountains, near Cloudcroft, New Mexico, circa 1904-1905; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 335)
      Inscription in negative: "Climbing the Sacramento Mts, near Cloudcroft, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
  - Santa Rita
    - View of an open pit copper mine, probably the Chino Mine, at Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1910-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 336)
      Inscription in negative: "The mines at Santa Rita, N.M. Photo by Irwin"
    - View of rail cars loaded with ore from Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1910-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 337)
    - View of the Santa Rita Store Company building in Santa Rita, New Mexico, circa 1910-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 338)
    - View of an open pit copper mine at Santa Rita, New Mexico, with the Kneeling Nun rock formation in the distance, circa 1910-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 339)
    - View of an open pit copper mine at Santa Rita, New Mexico, with the Kneeling Nun rock formation in the distance, circa 1910-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 340)
  - Silver City
    - View of cattle and a windmill and water tank near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 341)
      Inscription in negative: "Ranch scenes near Silver City, N.M. Photo by Irwin"
      Ink stamp on verso: Irwin's Studio, Silver City, N.M."
    - View of the New Mexico Cottage Sanatorium in Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 342)
      Inscription in negative: "Cottage Sanitorium, Silver City, N.M. Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a curving highway near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 343)
      Inscription in negative: "Along the highway near Silver City, New Mexico, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of Mogollon Creek near the Double S Ranch and Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 344)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "Mogollon Creek, flowing through the foot hills near the Double S Ranch, near Silver City, New Mexico, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a stream, probably Mogollon Creek near the Double S Ranch and Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 345)
    - View of Mogollon Creek near the Double S Ranch and Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 346)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "Along Mogollon Creek, around the Double S Ranch, near Silver City, New Mexico, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a dirt road next to a cliff near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 347)
      Inscription in negative: "Scenes along the highways near Silver City, N.M. Photo by Irwin"
    - View of flowering yucca plants near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 348)
      Inscription in negative: "Yucca Palms, near Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of Silver City, New Mexico, to the north from above, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 349)
      Inscription in negative: "Silver City, N.M., Looking north, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of the Territorial Normal School in Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 350)
      Inscription in negative: "State Teachers' College, Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of Bullard Street lined with automobiles in Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 351)
      Inscription in negative: "Bullard St., Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of yucca plants in bloom near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 352)
      Inscription in negative: "Forest of yucca palms near Silver City, N.M., Irwin
    - View of a snow-covered Bullard Street in Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 353)
      Inscription in negative: "Bullard St. in Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of yucca plants near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 354)
      Inscription in negative: "Yucca palms near Silver City, N.M., Irwin"
    - View of yucca plants in bloom near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 photographic postcards (Box 6, Folder 355)
      Inscription in negative: "Yucca palm near Silver City, N.M., Irwin"
    - View of Agave americana (century plant, maguey or American aloe) cactus near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 356)
      Inscription in negative: "Mescal cactus near Silver City, N.M., Irwin"
    - View of a herd of cattle on a dirt road near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 357)
      Inscription in negative: "In the Cow Country around Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of yucca plants in bloom near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 358)
      Inscription in negative: "Yuca palms near Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of donkey, a jenny nursing a foal in the vicinity of Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 359)
      Inscription in negative: "Around Silver City, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
  - Steeple Rock
    - Exterior portrait of two men and a woman posed by a windmill and porch at the ranch of Bob Glasfries? near Steeple Rock, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 360)
  - Sylvanite
    - View of Sylvanite, New Mexico, circa 1908; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 361)
      Inscription in negative: "Sylvanite, New Mex., A mushroom mining camp during a gold excitement, Irwin"
  - Tyrone
    - Overhead view of Tyrone, New Mexico, circa 1915-1921; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 362)
      Inscription in negative: "Tyrone, N.M. Photo by Irwin"
    - View of an open pit copper mine at Tyrone, New Mexico, circa 1915-1921; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 363)
      Inscription in negative: "Around the mines at Tyrone, N.M., Irwin"
  - Unidentified Locations in New Mexico
    - View of flowering yucca plants, probably in New Mexico, circa 1925; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored (Box 7, Folder 364)
      Print signed by Era Bock on the recto
    - View of flowering yucca plants, probably in New Mexico, circa 1925; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored (Box 7, Folder 365)
    - View of an automobile on a winding dirt road and buildings by a river, probably in New Mexico, 1926 February; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored (Box 7, Folder 366)
      Inscription on verso: "By Era Bock, Feb. 1926"
    - View of a herd of cattle on a dirt road with a man and partially obscured truck, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 367)
    - Exterior portrait of two men posed sitting in a hunting camp next to a tent and a deer carcass, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 368)
    - Exterior portrait of two dogs next to the carcass of a puma, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 369)
    - View of a stream and a forest of conifer trees, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 370)
    - View of a river and banks, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 371)
    - View of cacti on a rocky slope, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 372)
    - View of flowering yucca plants, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 3 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 373)
    - View of a church and surrounding buildings, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 374)
    - Exterior portrait of two dogs by the edge of a water body, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 375)
      Inscription on verso: "Guards around the ranch"
    - View of a sheep herd grazing among conifer trees, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 376)
    - Exterior portrait of a man riding a donkey in a parade, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 377)
      Inscription on recto: "Old prospector"
    - View of a dirt road through conifer trees, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 378)
    - View of flowering yucca plants, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 379)
    - View of a dirt road running parallel to a river, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 380)
    - View of conifer trees along a road, railroad tracks, and a body of water, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 381)
    - View of a river, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 382)
    - View of a river with tree-covered banks and low hills in the distance, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 383)
    - View of a river with a dirt road alongside, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 384)
    - View of horses on a hill, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 385)
    - View of buildings and a tall chimney, probably a smelter in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 386)
    - View of a horse with a saddle by a yucca and cactus, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 photographic postcards (Box 7, Folder 387)
      Inscription in negative: "Cow horse worth while, Photo by Irwin"
    - View of five donkeys and a foal, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 388)
    - Exterior portrait of a man with the carcasses of two pumas, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 389)
    - View of a road in a canyon, identified as a highway between Silver City and Clifton, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 390)
      Inscription in negative: "Along the Silver City Clifton Highway, Irwin"
    - View of cactus and yucca plants, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 391)
    - View of a desert landscape with yucca and cactus, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 392)
    - View of Yucca gloriosa (Spanish dagger) plants in southern New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 7, Folder 393)
      Inscription in negative: "The Spanish Dagger of Southern N.M., Irwin"
    - View of a house with an automobile, identified as Bear Creek Ranch, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 394)
      Inscriptions on verso: "Bear Creek Ranch" and "30"
    - View of an automobile on a dirt road among rocky hills, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 395)
    - View of an automobile on a dirt road among rocky hills, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 396)
    - View of a dirt road among rocky hills, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 397)
    - View of cattle near a watering hole in a fenced desert landscape, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 398)
      Pencil inscription on verso: "Watering places on the desert"
    - View of a donkey and a foal, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 399)
    - View of a donkey and a foal, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 400)
    - View of a bear in the canopy of a deciduous tree from below, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 401)
      Ink stamp on verso: "11"
    - Exterior portrait of man and a boy posed kneeling with three hunting dogs and the carcass of a bear, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 402)
    - Exterior portrait of man and a boy posed standing with three hunting dogs and the carcass of a bear, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 403)
    - Exterior portrait of two men and a boy posed kneeling with four hunting dogs and the carcass of a bear, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 404)
    - Exterior portrait of a man posed standing with a hunting dog and the carcass of a bear, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 405)
      Ink stamp on verso: "3"
    - View of a dirt road running parallel to a river, as well as an automobile parked off the road, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 406)
    - View of a dirt road running parallel to a river, as well as an automobile parked off the road, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 407)
    - View of a dirt road running parallel to a river, as well as an automobile parked off the road, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 408)
    - View of a river with trees and low hills, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 409)
    - Exterior portrait of four women posed standing on an iron bridge, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 410)
    - View of a river with trees and low hills, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 411)
    - View of a river with brush on its banks, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 412)
    - View of a dirt road through a forest of conifer trees, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 413)
    - View of a dirt road with an automobile among conifer trees, probably in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored (Box 7, Folder 414)
    - Views of a visit to a four-story high pueblo, probably in New Mexico, by a man, woman, and child, circa 1920-1930; 3 photographic negatives (Box 7, Folder 415)
      Accompanied by an original envelope with an inscription "NM, 3 of 3"
  - Photocollages of New Mexico Sites
    - Photocollage that positions discrete portraits of two boys posed standing and crying with a cactus in New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 photographic postcards (Box 7, Folder 416)
      Inscription in negative: "Young Pioneers on the Deserts of New Mex., Photo by Irwin"
    - Photocollage of six views of sites in New Mexico with the title "Spend Your Vacation in New Mexico, the Land of Romance"; sites include Springerville Road, a Navajo Indian dance in Gallup, Taos Pueblo, and Pueblo Bonito, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 7, Folder 417)
- Oklahoma Territory and Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; Series VII; 1.25; (1 box)
  Series VIII is organized into fifteen subseries: Anadarko, Cache, Caddo County, Chickasha, Choctaw Nation, Davis, Duncan, Fort Reno, Fort Sill, Gotebo, Minco, Mountain View, Oakdale, Washita River, and Unidentified Locations in Indian Territory and Oklahoma Territory
  This series chiefly consists of views of sites and scenes in the separate territories of Oklahoma Territory and Indian Territory, which later combined to become the state of Oklahoma. Images include American Indian settlements and structures, as well as views of American Indians at identified locations in the territories. Many images also document deer and fowl hunting parties in the territories.
  - Anadarko
    - View of the Washita River, with two men and a girl, posed standing on the river bank, one man holding a rifle, near Anadarko, Indian Territory, 1898 May 7; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 418)
      Inscription on recto: "Views along the Washita Riv. near Anadarko, O.T., May 7th 1898"
    - Exterior portrait of men standing outside of Hotel Anadarko in Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 419)
    - View of the exterior of the Presbyterian Mission at Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 420)
      Inscription on recto: "Presbyterian Mission at Anadarko, I.T."
    - View of horses grazing near a Native American settlement, Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 421)
      Inscription on recto: "Bird's-eye-view of Anadarko, I.T."
    - View of horse-drawn wagons, tipis, and people, Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 422)
      Inscription on recto of mounted print: "Scenes on issue day at Anadarko"
    - View of a stream, one man standing, one man on a horse, and a farm house and buildings, Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 423)
      Inscription on recto: "Views around Anadarko, I.T."
    - View of horse-drawn wagons, some covered, and people, gathered outside a picket fence. Anadarko, Indian Territory, 1894 July 4; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 424)
      Inscription on recto: "Views around Anadarko, July 4, 1894"
    - View of an Apache Camp with a mounted figure in the foreground, near Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 425)
      Inscription on recto: "Apache camp near Anadarko, I.T."
      Inscription on negative of print: "33"
    - View of three Apache children seated on the ground outside a tipi, Apache Camp near Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print and 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 8, Folder 426)
      Inscription on recto: "Scene in an Apache camp near Anadarko"
      Inscription on negative of print: "32"
    - View of a wagon, tents, and animal pelts hung on a line in an Apache camp near Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 427)
      Inscription on recto: "Apache Indian Camp near Anadarko, O. T."
    - View of Wichita grass house and small structure near Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 8, Folder 428)
      Inscription on recto: "Wichita Indian grass house near Anadarko"